Artem Timofeev

May 25, 1994

Contact

LinkedIn: Artem Timofeev

E-mail: atimofeev@tuta.io

Phone: +995 551114058

Github: https://github.com/atimofeev

As a DevOps Engineer at Devexperts, I've worked with complex trading systems and other financial solutions for top brokers, ensuring high availability, scalability, and performance. I use various AI tools on a daily basis to increase productivity and for problem-solving, and I enjoy automating routine tasks and reducing manual involvement in processes.

I have over eight years of experience in supporting and engineering roles within the fintech industry. Furthermore, I have strong skills in Linux system administration, configuration management, containerization, orchestration, monitoring, and cloud technologies. I love learning and trying new things, and I am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to grow.

Employment

DevexpertsDevOps Engineer

May 2021 — Apr 2023 Tbilisi, Georgia

- Linux systems administration and automation
- Production platforms troubleshooting
- 24/7 critical incidents resolution
- Configuration management (Git, BitBucket)
- Regular deployments and monitoring setup for specific scenarios (TeamCity, Ansible)
- Automation of support and maintenance operations (Ansible, Bash)
- Scaling and maintenance of existing systems (Terraform, Consul, Nomad, Pacemaker)
- Cisco ASA firewall rules configuration
- Configuration of webservers/proxies (nginx, HAproxy, envoy)

Dec 2014 — May 2021 Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Tecnhical Support Specialist

- B2B customer support for complex trading systems and other financial solutions for top brokers
- Production platforms monitoring (Zabbix, Grafana, custom internal monitoring services)
- Incident management and issue escalation (Jira, Slack, IP Telephony)
- Communication with business clients, who have first line customer support on their side
- Java application logs analysis for incident resolution
- Bash scripting for small tasks automation
- Regular manual QA checks on Prod and Staging platforms
- Frequent SQL query writing for collection of various data from DB (PostgreSQL)
- Writing technical documentation for existing and new processes, expanding common KB (Confluence)
- Mentoring of new specialists and knowledge sharing

Education

2010 — 2014 Saint-Petersburg State Polytechnic University, Software engineering for computers

and computer-based systems, Specialist

Additional education: English language in scope of professional technical commu-

nication

Used Tools

Editor and Notes: Doom Emacs, Org Mode

Version Control: GitHub, Bitbucket, Gitlab, Subversion

Programming Languages: Python, Bash, JavaScript

Infrastructure/Configuration: Terraform, Ansible

Containerization/Orchestration: Docker, Nomad, Kubernetes

Monitoring: Zabbix, Prometheus, Grafana, ELK

Databases: PostgreSQL, Amazon RDS, Redis

CI/CD Tools: TeamCity, GitHub Actions, Gitlab CI/CD, Jenkins

Cloud Platforms: AWS (VPC, IAM, S3, EC2, RDS, CodeBuild/CodeDeploy, ECR, ECS, EKS)

Other

Languages: advanced English, native Russian

Hobbies:

- Music creation: digital modular synthesizers for generative ambient and noise
- Making DYI projects: electronics, 3D modeling and printing, including custom self developed processes automation (jinja2, GCODE)
- Moutain biking: 10 years of experience in Downhill, Enduro, Pump Track and BMX racing
- Hiking in the mountains